<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[that mystic statistic...]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[that mystic statistic...]]></description>
        <link>http://mysticstatistic.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 21:31:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://mysticstatistic.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 21:30:59 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Planning Intelligence Product (2 of 6)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Planning Intelligence Product (2 of 6)</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/932e9e99-3bec-4e27-af38-75e4a5d19a9a.jpg">,<h2>What are you going to learn in this blog</h2>,<p>You're going to learn about what we've used in regard to planning activity and managing the delivery cycle. You're going to see our cycle, and how we managed backlog. And you're going to see that as a function we flex based on need of customer. Customer is, after all… King. You're also going to learn than 6 months after setting up a new team, certain process are still quite fluid and dynamic as we settle into what works for us.</p>,<p>Right, before we start let's recognise that there's a cycle of activity in the planning section. You engage, then capture, record and schedule(=planning=this bit), deliver, review and restart. But the planning side is key, I've seen teams that haven't got a good handle on planning undermine their credibility and really struggle to demonstrate value because they'll start moving into a place where triage is a method of prioritising and that's not a good place to be.</p>,<h2>Some background for us</h2>,<p>When I created the initial team, our whole purpose was corporate disruption. Not to undermine, I mean positive disruption… to challenge the status quo by demonstrating things could be better. Teams that are setup purposefully to disrupt have less of a need for a structured work program and are more poised to be opportunistic and tactical in regard to delivery of work - so a very uncontrolled start, and a waterfall-esque delivery; because it's just not just technology you are introducing, it's softer, it's culture change and reprogramming your customer to think differently. I mention this because when you develop a core team whose purpose is to disrupt, it's uniquely difficult to move to a model or robustness, governance and control; I've already bred that out of their DNA. Using chemicals, in the water. Sssshh don't tell them. Fortunately, the same chemicals affect their hearing.</p>,<p>Considering our now-genetic disposition to set things on fire, the first area of planning and control was needed when we became a bigger team; all of a sudden the pipe that was pumping us work become orders of magnitude fatter. No longer did we need to hunt for work - it was coming at us full pelt. What I wanted to do was introduce a means of capturing everything but putting the onus of individual prioritisation back on the business - I'm not equipped with the right information to prioritise effort frankly I just want to work on the cool stuff. They're the best people to prioritise all I needed to do was setup a mechanism and development roadmap and we could populate it.</p>,<p>To try and explain it there's a really simple and nasty looking diagram below.</p>,<h2>Tools for the fools</h2>,<p>We basically use a very loose agile based development approach. We have a sprint plan, where I annualise the amount of hours for each directorate based on how my team is funded, and then annualise then split that up neatly for services so each directorate and service can see when they're next getting a 2 or 4 week development slot. We then encourage each service owner to provide us user stories for each bit of work, and work with them to capture enough detail so that when the sprint comes around we're just pointing and squirting development time at it. Sounds simple right?</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/1911003c-9a6d-48d1-a7fa-3480483d2fa9.png">,<p>To capture user stories we use Gitlab the free version. It's pretty powerful, it allows us to label stories, add comments and capture requirements to our need, as well as plan sprints and roadmaps. Management also love pinning and moving stories between stages - you know what they're like, anything shiny! (literally just talking about me) Until recently, we've held access to just my team, but we're about to open the tool up so we can share it with large customers, with the dream being that customers can add their own user stories. It won't happen mass market but if a few do it, then that's a step forward. I've not really got any other comment on GitLAB other than we know it does a bunch of other stuff around versioning and code store but we literally only use it for the user story and sprint planning. I am keen to keep documentation to a minimum level that allows effective support without being a substantial overhead, and as our products start to get with the program, they'll start self documenting functional requirements and the world will be a better place.</p>,<blockquote>Side note : in the coming weeks I&apos;ll be pointing a PowerBI report at it to get some progress reporting out to the business so if anyone&apos;s interested in accessing that when it&apos;s done, hit me up; I&apos;ll probs post it up with a short post.</blockquote>,<h2>My team, my problems.</h2>,<p>So there's the obvious "we're a new team" challenges. For example, pointing user stories is like pulling teeth. Everybody has their own niche service experience, and if you ask someone from a children's background to try and point stories for corporate, there are blank looks and lots of questions. "whats the data structure", "where does it live?", "whats a UPN" all legitimate questions, but reflecting the experience gap that we'll develop over time. We're pivoting that issue by pointing in smaller groups now with people used to working on the same types of data; it'll take longer to have a consistent view of story complexity but I think is a more productive way of spinning up.</p>,<p>We're also struggling to get the business to engage and test during the sprint, so we have a clumsy period of time that kind of reminds me of a sketch where a zombie is trying to chase a victim and stumbling around doing a terrible job - that's what it's like trying to get a customer to UAT and sign off a product. We're actively working on improving that, and may get to the point soon where we won't commit to start a sprint unless the business has resources allocated to test it in that sprint. If you're starting off in an agile way, I'd recommend you engage beforehand and articulate that your customers need to commit time to the sprint itself to test or it will fail.</p>,<p>Then there's training; it's a real challenge. We've learnt not to try and train someone with a dashboards that uses their own data, because they'll pay no attention to how to use a dashboard, and navigate, drill up, down, filter etc. They get lost in the narrative of their own data. This is fine when it's an operational tool, providing insights because we're experts in that, but when it's reflecting performance data, we get the performance team in to talk them through. This might be unique to our structure - I think typically services devolve report production and not centralise it, and when it's centralised it's usually done alongside performance, but ours is unique. Special!</p>,<p>To help in training we're focussing on creating a suite of templates that bake in a stock look and feel. I've resisted templates for years, feeling that properly educated designers with some UX background will make better presentational decisions than templates can allow and really flex the product to best meet the topic. The problem is, we need to get to a consistent level of design skills and that's planned up taking some time. We'll get there, but until then for the majority of product we'll template.</p>,<h2>While talking about structure…</h2>,<p>My team structure is below, it's nice and simple, it doesn't cover all posts but it gets across the jist. Now within local government our business is broken down into directorates; different councils work differently largely we have Childrens, Adults, Corporate, and Business / Highways. The relationship and engagement piece is handled by the team managers and they act as points of contact for the directorates. I just float around doing things pointing at objects and swearing a lot.</p>,<h3>Team Managers role in planning &amp; management</h3>,<p>My team managers meet at least once a month with each of the service heads in the business. There's probably 100 services across the authority, but some have the same leads. In those sessions, we the team manager will review GitLAB with the head of service make changes, and discuss the planning of the next activities. We'll also hopefully talk about upcoming impacts, changes to policy or legislation that might have knocks on, as well as projects that might need to be mentioned. There's also a large discussion about ad hoc activities. As part of the restructure we onboarded people into the team from services and everyone that came brought their own workload, and channels of effort. All work was produced manually in excel using reports from the system at the front end whilst some came with SQL knowledge. We continue to chip away at the internal inefficiencies while working on the organisations data transformation program, but right now, and for probably the next year, up to 50% of team activity is manual, routine heavy repeated work driven by legislation or ad hoc query.</p>,<p>We make sure that the ad hoc query impact factors in how we prioritise that work though - clearly if it's causing us some overhead then we'll care about getting it done sooner.</p>,<p>That discussion then is fed up to a directorate board, where we can challenge and debate each services needs against the available time. I have someone from the directorate chair that, so it's a self-fulfilling session - the business are directing the teams effort, and prioritising themselves. The board meets monthly reviews progress, tackles dependencies and prioritises, and we can focus on what we're good at - smashing it out.</p>,<h2>What have we learned boys &amp; girls?</h2>,<p>So that's our planning cycle. I've told you about the journey we've been on, some of the challenges we faced and continue to face. The technology we use and process… the engagement model which teases our planning, and escalation and prioritisation process. What I haven't talked about is technology and solution planning and I'll cover that in the next blog. I'd challenge anybody that said their model worked brilliantly while at the same time moving at a good pace, and I stand by the decisions we've made and steps we've taken. We've work to do, but we're becoming much more robust daily. Fun fun fun!!!</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://mysticstatistic.com/planning-intelligence-product-2-of-6/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d9321c1e-5262-47ff-929d-783751b6bdfc</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 21:30:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The grind : Idea Generation (1 of 6)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/041142c4-e5a8-4a63-8fcf-e9f19282655a.png">,<h1>The grind : Idea Generation (1 of 6)</h1>,<p>So for my first blog I thought I'd talk you through our delivery cycle, with one blog per section, stuff we do as a team and any lessons we've learnt that we might spare you from being burnt from. The sections as we see them are</p>,<ol><li>Idea Generation</li><li>Planning &amp; Management</li><li>Delivery</li><li>Sign off</li></ol>,<p>And a couple of supporting elements</p>,<ol><li>Engagement</li><li>Strategy</li></ol>,<p>If this is your first read, i’d recommend reading the “about me” section, as it’s useful background.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://mysticstatistic.com/the-grind-idea-generation-1-of-6/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e96d59bb-e528-4142-aff3-8bf585d1de03</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 22:19:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[#whoami]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>#whoami</h1>,<p>I'm a 38 year old dad of 3, I've lived in the north east all my life and my family are all local. I was never really particularly academic; I left school and went to college which was basically an excuse to get drunk, then got a job in IT when I was 19 for a small computer company called Performance Computers as an engineer. After a bunch of years there I went to work for Santander in their call centre - on the phones initially then onto a resource planning role where I always brought in a bunch of software to help planning.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9f2b981a-aa45-4187-b836-f52bc1cf0f53.jpg">,<p>I met my wife, fancied a change and applied for a job in business change. Landed it, and that was the beginning of the beginning.</p>,<p>Now having worked in local government for over a decade I've had the pleasure a number of different roles; business change, project managing technology deployments - I've even managed a business support team delivering blue badges which was actually really helpful grounding - it's easy for nerds to forget or disconnect from the effect of their decisions and keeping that line of sight from action to social impact is now very important to me.</p>,<p>I like to joke that I'm definitely not a "Bobby best practise" - I do research a lot but often stray from the common path others have tread. I'd probably like to sum myself up as a data driven disruptive technologist…, Which is a gob full but wraps up all my passions and a bit of my personality to boot. I've been fortunate enough to combine these traits in what I can only describe as a hurricane of education and experience over the past 5 years - definitely the most exciting 5 years of my career.</p>,<h2>More relevant stuffs</h2>,<p>In 2010, when this journey first started - I had used crystal reports with some prebuilt sql queries that we had developed as part of a CRM implementation that had just finished in the contact centre. One of my first mistakes was bringing aforementioned CRM to a shuddering halt with a cartesian join so horrible that one of the DBA's looked at me like I'd slapped his wife. Looking back, it was pretty bad and taught me that DBA's love their work on average more than their spouses and you can't wing it on a production environment. With that I set out on a mission.</p>,<p>My mission began in 2010 when I went on a SQL Server 2008 r2 full stack course. I also had a daughter and got married but I still managed to spend every possible moment learning SSIS and SSAS Multi Dimensional. By 2011 I had a multi dimensional cube setup driving data from our CRM; it must have been half decent because the DBA who hadn't made eye contact with me since what we refer to now as “the day a bit of him died” peer reviewed it and didn't want to punch me in the neck. Even the supplier of the CRM hit me up for details on the build.</p>,<p>2012 I moved into our IT department seconded into a role to pop out a few tactical BI solutions, mostly using SSIS, SSAS and SSRS. By 2014 I'd done enough decent deployments to get a small team and by 2016 there was talk of a restructure. 2017 that happened and now through what I can only presume is a series of terrible decisions by my employers I manage a team of 30 people smashing out stuff for the whole council. And here we are - knee deep in a stew of opportunity and challenge, waking up each day with a smile on my face.</p>,<h3>Before you move onto reading things.</h3>,<p>Consider all of that when you read my stuff. I'm not a pedigree data scientist with 20 years behind me, nor am I some business management doctorate with a 50 year plan and a strategy document for my strategy documents. I'm a gobby “data driven disruptive technologist” who was able to couple an understanding of what the clients needed - particularly in local government - with an ability to execute. Consider that before you listen to any of my advice, I'm just the same as anyone in your data team driven my a passion to do cool stuff.</p>,<p>~JK</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://mysticstatistic.com/whoami/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">84a914e3-b9a2-44e2-88b8-19407ebe9cd7</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 21:44:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerPork/PowerBI]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>So a colleague and I pulled together a powerbi file that leverages the Rosette API - a text analytics service with a free tier pricing model. We use it to analyse groups of text for local government, typically social care outputs and thought it might be useful for others… so feel free to download and use. It’s got an example in there for your viewing pleasure.</p>,<article><img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/ffcfc16a817adad73e4278fef27b80e9/noop?input=https%3A%2F%2Favatars2.githubusercontent.com%2Fu%2F23039305%3Fv%3D3%26s%3D400"><h1>PowerPork/PowerBI</h1><p>PowerBI stuff</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/PowerPork/PowerBI</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e1c5004a-5a14-4aeb-806c-c9e844912e62</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 08:38:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>