<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[that mystic statistic...]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[that mystic statistic...]]></description>
        <link>http://mysticstatistic.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 20:34:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://mysticstatistic.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 20:34:56 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Data maturity modelling]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Data maturity modelling</h1>,<p>and the link between data maturity and solution design.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/666fcd64-d93c-4024-8012-5bf772c290a9.png">,<p>Local government has many verticals, so many it may perhaps be the most diverse organisation you could work within. Even if you compare with some of the giant multi market orgs (for example, Tesco's who in banking, shopping, groceries, property etc). We have so many different types of services that approaching all of them at the same level of depth for a team even our size is a real challenge. It's impractical to take the 'narrow and deep' model, invest in one area and showcase it because the need for data and analytics is across the piece. Having said that, there can be a frustration of the broad and shallow approach doesn't address those services which are a little further up the maturity scale. And then there’s the question of investment in time…</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://mysticstatistic.com/data-maturity-modelling/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">6d159509-e188-49fd-bce4-08226b11e27e</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 10:54:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Planning Intelligence Product (2 of 6)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Planning Intelligence Product (2 of 6)</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/932e9e99-3bec-4e27-af38-75e4a5d19a9a.jpg">,<h2>What are you going to learn in this blog</h2>,<p>You're going to learn about what we've used in regard to planning activity and managing the delivery cycle. You're going to see our cycle, and how we managed backlog. And you're going to see that as a function we flex based on need of customer. Customer is, after all… King. You're also going to learn than 6 months after setting up a new team, certain process are still quite fluid and dynamic as we settle into what works for us.</p>,<p>Right, before we start let's recognise that there's a cycle of activity in the planning section. You engage, then capture, record and schedule(=planning=this bit), deliver, review and restart. But the planning side is key, I've seen teams that haven't got a good handle on planning undermine their credibility and really struggle to demonstrate value because they'll start moving into a place where triage is a method of prioritising and that's not a good place to be.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://mysticstatistic.com/planning-intelligence-product-2-of-6/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d9321c1e-5262-47ff-929d-783751b6bdfc</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 21:58:08 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The grind : Idea Generation (1 of 6)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/041142c4-e5a8-4a63-8fcf-e9f19282655a.png">,<h1>The grind : Idea Generation (1 of 6)</h1>,<p>So for my first blog I thought I'd talk you through our delivery cycle, with one blog per section, stuff we do as a team and any lessons we've learnt that we might spare you from being burnt from. The sections as we see them are</p>,<ol><li>Idea Generation</li><li>Planning &amp; Management</li><li>Delivery</li><li>Sign off</li></ol>,<p>And a couple of supporting elements</p>,<ol><li>Engagement</li><li>Strategy</li></ol>,<p>If this is your first read, i’d recommend reading the “about me” section, as it’s useful background.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://mysticstatistic.com/the-grind-idea-generation-1-of-6/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e96d59bb-e528-4142-aff3-8bf585d1de03</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 22:19:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[#whoami]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>#whoami</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/9f2b981a-aa45-4187-b836-f52bc1cf0f53.jpg">,<p>I read blogs all the time from people I admire and respect (and secretly a few people that do my head in) and I think sometimes it’s helpful to know a little behind the poster. So… here ya go.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://mysticstatistic.com/whoami/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">84a914e3-b9a2-44e2-88b8-19407ebe9cd7</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 21:44:21 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PowerPork/PowerBI]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>So a colleague and I pulled together a powerbi file that leverages the Rosette API - a text analytics service with a free tier pricing model. We use it to analyse groups of text for local government, typically social care outputs and thought it might be useful for others… so feel free to download and use. It’s got an example in there for your viewing pleasure.</p>,<article><img src="https://imgflo.herokuapp.com/graph/2b2431f8e7ba7b0/ffcfc16a817adad73e4278fef27b80e9/noop?input=https%3A%2F%2Favatars2.githubusercontent.com%2Fu%2F23039305%3Fv%3D3%26s%3D400"><h1>PowerPork/PowerBI</h1><p>PowerBI stuff</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/PowerPork/PowerBI</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e1c5004a-5a14-4aeb-806c-c9e844912e62</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 08:38:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>